# Curriculum vitae

## Jacek Abramczyk

**Country** Sweden

*Mobile no.* +48 500 357 338

e-mail jacek.abramczyk@gmail.com

Website http://jrabramczyk.com



## **PROFILE**

Accomplished solution architect with experience in .Net/C# since 2008. I have advanced competence in area of code optimization/performance, multi-threading, algorithms, business logic and database design. I'm very experienced with Object Oriented Programming/Design, Test Driven Development and SCRUM. I also have extensive background in full life-cycle of software development process including requirements gathering, design, coding, testing, debugging and maintenance.

Currently I improve my skills in the areas of architecture design and team management. I also constatnly improve my skills in C++, F# and finance sector.

# **KEY SKILLS**

Languages C#, SQL, JavaScript, F# (basic), C++ (basic)

Technologies ASP .Net (MVC), AngularJS, WCF, LINQ, BigData, Multithreading, MSMQ, jQuery,

Quartz.Net

DBMS MSSQL, Oracle, ElasticSearch, MongoDB, Couchbase, SSIS

Architecture SaaS, Client-Server, SOA, Microservices, DDD(basic), Onion architecture

Principles OOP/OOD, TDD, SOLID

Patterns IoC, Lazy Loading, DI, Interceptor, Factory, Singleton, Repository, ...

CI TeamCity, Hudson/Jenkins, TFS

Team work SVN, Git, TFS, Agile, Scrum, Pair-programming

Bug tracking TFS, JIRA, VersionOne, Rally, IBM SCCD

Others Entity Framework 6.1, ReSharper, Matlab(basic), BPM Metastorm

Testing nUnit, Moq, Ninject, Windsor Castle, AutoFixture, nCrunch, Jasmine, AutoFac

## WORK EXPERIENCE

7.2017 – Senior IT Consultant at SEB Bank



MiFID II is the Markets in Financial Instruments Directive

- Design solution for two required functionalities LossReporting and Cost&Charges
- Implementation, testing and deploy final solution
- Work in SCRUM team, direct contact with business e.g. derivative experts

Technologies .Net 4.6, C#, MSSQL, EF 6.1, Autofac, nUnit, Web API, TDD, Micro Services

12.2016 - 7.2017



## **Technologies**

1.2016 - 12.2016



# **Technologies**

8.2015 - 1.2016



# **Technologies**

8.2014 - 8.2015





# Senior Full Stack Developer/Contractor at Thomson Reuters

Supplier Reporting project —web based tool allowing final user to modify and map data relating to income and outcome of products we sell or buy. Mainly selling market data to investment banks, monitor that and create reports to see which products gives us most money. Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Direct contact with customers to get feedback from them about our project, propose new solutions, functionalities
- All 3 developers spread around the world (only online contact)
- Looking for new frameworks, solutions to implement new functionalities

.Net 4.5, C#, TDD, Agile, Continuous Delivery, Jenkins, VS 2015, ReSharper, Oracle, AngularJS, ASP .Net MVC, Web API, jQuery, JavaScript, Quartz .Net

# Senior IT Consultant at Credit Suisse - UK London

EPE Primo project, gathering detailed information about trades, derivatives, equities and other investment banks products in the purpose of performance Monte Carlo simulation and other advanced calculations to measure risk of investments for Bank's Regulators.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Increase performance dramatically (in 2017 we will reach 10 times more trades and have the same amount of time to perform calculation)
- Multithreading, Parallel programming, Performance optimization
- Grid, Processes management to reduce CPU usage of single node

.Net 4.5, C#, TDD, Agile/Scrum, TeamCity, SVN, VS 2013, MSSQL 2012, ReSharper, MSMQ, WCF, RhinoMock, nUnit, JIRA

## Senior Software Developer at Achilles Group Limited – UK London

Improve and fix bugs in web application responsible for gathering buyers and suppliers so they can search one another.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Improve performance, mostly DB layer
- Migrate data from SQL Server into Couchbase

SaaS, Couchbase, SQL Server, Asp.Net MVC, Multithreading, C#, SCRUM

## **Senior IT Contractor**

## SANTANDER CONSUMER BANK

Web application for employees of Santander Bank mainly helps in setting new agreements, creating new customers etc. Whole application is written in ASP.Net Web Forms, business logic is mostly done in JavaScript.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Implementation in accordance with the requirements of documentation and architect's comments
- Creating SSIS packages and follow SOA (Service Oriented Architecture) principles

# TITIAN

Develop comprehensive software platform, purpose-built for the management of samples, including: compounds, biologicals, reagents. Designed to provide rest-assured sample inventory, tracking and an error-free supply chain, Software can streamline sample management workflows for maximum efficiency and in-house productivity.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Refactor design solution (code is not consistent with SOLID) and remove legacy code
- Implement new functionalities using TDD

### **THOMSON REUTERS**

Design new solution for application responsible for logging (40-80) millions of events every week. Migrate data from SQL Server into MongoDB and ElasticSearch, compare solutions in terms of performance and data usage.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:





- Investigate ability to migrate tens of millions records of data from SQL into NoSQL Database (ElasticSearch and MongoDB)
- Design, test, implement and deploy tool for migration
- Compare performance of SQL Server, ElasticSearch and MongoDB
- Find useful tools and libraries e.g. NEST which is .Net client for ElasticSearch
- Refactor old code to improve performance

#### 2.2014 - 8.2014

## Software Engineer at Powel sp. z o. o.



System responsible for exchange data in the Nordic energy market with focus on very secure, fast and what's more reliable way because of very sensitive information and domain usage. Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Estimate tasks including tests that are necessary to cover bigger part of code. During development we were focus on TDD and DDD
- Improving performance by parallel programming, remove legacy and 3<sup>rd</sup> party code
- Code review especially of newest and youngest employees
- Design solution (architecture, technologies, patterns)
- Extreme programming (Pair-programming), Micro-pairing

# **Technologies**

.Net 4.5, C#, MSMQ, Ninject, nUnit, WCF, Code Contracts, Onion Architecture, TDD, DDD, Pair-programming, Parallel programming, LINQ, Oracle

#### 8.2012 - 2.2014

# .Net Developer at Atena financial and IT services S.A.



Web application for insurance adjusters to manage process of damages. System helps employees make a decision of compensate for damages when customer had an accident, loss or injury.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Estimate tasks, design and implement functionalities
- Read business documentation and write technical one
- Write documentation and requirements based on customer needs
- Maintenance old functionalities
- Design database, improve long old stored procedures and migrate them into code
- Refactor old functionalities using OOP, SOLID and TDD
- Parallel programming, lazy loading and caching data in order to improve performance
- Aspect oriented programming (AOP) for logging and try catch statements
- Direct contact with customer and business analyst

# **Technologies**

ASP .Net 3.5, C#, JavaScript (jQuery, knockout.js), WCF, nUnit, Moq, WindsorCastle, TDD, T-SQL, MSSQL, BPM Metastorm, SVN

## 5.2012 - 8.2012

#### .Net Developer at Hakon Software sp. z o. o.



Desktop application created for dental companies which require management of patients, history of treatments and past diseases. Book future visits and create detailed plan of treatments. Many additional functionalities for dentists.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Gather requirements from dentists then design and implement functionalities
- Migrate new customer's data from different systems
- Design database and system components

## **Technologies**

Windows Forms, C#, .Net 2.0, MVS 2008, MSSQL

2.2011 - 11.2011

# Software Engineer at Smart Systems sp. z o. o.

Project created in order to make call center more efficient. Whole information of clients were stored in Microsoft Office Excel files so it was hard to looking for information, sort it, change it and what's more share it by 30 employees at the same time.

Responsibilities/Main challenges:

- Design, Implement, Configure and Deploy whole platform from scratch
- Design database and move data from Excel files into database ensure transactions
- Design website which provide all required functionalities
- Design module that can make statistics about individual employee's results

**Technologies** 

PHP, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Ajax, JavaScript, Windows Server 2003

2009 - 2011

# Freelance projects

**Projects** 

- 1. CMS Web MVC applications provided rent apartments and online shops functionalities.
  - C#, ASP.Net MVC, EF
- 2. Several websites for individual people, mostly 3 page websites without complicated logic. All projects were done using PHP, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL/MySQL.

## **CERTIFICATE**

Microsoft

Course 6654: Introducing to Windows Communication Foundation

## **EDUCATION**

2014

Master of Computer science and Mathematics, Department of Software Engineering, Gdansk University of Technology

Main subjects:

- Parallel processing CUDA/CELL
- Base analysis of capital markets
- High performance computing systems
- Advanced technology of DB

2012

Bachelor of Computer science and Mathematics, Department of Algorithms and System Modeling, Gdansk University of Technology Main subjects:

- Mathematical analysis and linear algebra
- Algorithms and data structure
- Discrete mathematics
- Numerical methods
- Probability and mathematical statistics
- Physics
- Computer architecture
- Analysis of algorithms
- Artificial intelligence MATLAB
- Object oriented programming

# HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Algoithm www.hackerrank.com, www.spoj.pl - Looking for new solutions in algorithm problems, code optimization

Activities Chess, basketball, gym, swimming, running, squash and dancing (salsa & bachata)

**Books** Psychology (motivation, emotional intelligence), Investing

"I hereby agree for processing my personal data, included in my job offer, for the purpose of recruitment (as defined in the Act of August 29, 1997 on the Protection of Personal Data (Journal of Laws No. 133, item 883)."